Okay, so in this video then, we are going
to discuss two very important artifacts.
One is called the Team Charter and the
other one is called the Resource Calendar.
Okay, so let's talk about the Team
Charter.
Now the Team Charter is considered an
output of Plan Resource Management.
One of the outputs of
Plan Resource Management
Plan, which we covered in a prior video.
and the resource management plan is
documenting procedures, documenting how.
The team charter is another artifact
that's considered an output, if you like,
of the resource management plan.
And the team charter
is basically documenting
the do's and don'ts of the team, right?
It's documenting shared values,
right?
The teams shared values, their agreements,
operating guidelines, you know,
what we should say, how we should behave,
right?
That is all documented in the team chart.
And that is especially the case when you
have team members in, you know,
many different locations, right,
and especially in foreign countries where
there might be also some cultural
differences as well, right?
So this is really what
the team charter is going
to be documented, the
do's and don'ts of the team.
And one very important aspect of that is
it's a collaborative process, right?
the team collaborates to create this
document.
It is not something
that the project manager
is going to be delegating to team members.
The project manager is not writing this
and then sending it to team members.
These are the rules that we have to
follow.
No, this is a collaborative process.
Everybody is involved.
All the team members, should I say,
are involved in creating the team charter.
So basically because we are a.
agreeing, team members are agreeing to
their values, right?
So it's a team shared values, agreements,
and operating guidelines.
And this is for both predictive projects
as well as agile projects.
So in both cases, it's a collaborative
process.
So things like, for example, specific time
commitments, expectations of team members,
that's all going to be documented here,
right?
How are we going to communicate,
right, guidelines for communication?
What tools are we going to be using to
communicate with one another?
Especially, you know,
you've got team members
in working remotely in
foreign countries, right?
There might not be any overlap of office
hours.
So how do we handle those kind of
constraints to communication?
That would be documented here as well.
What tools we are going to be using?
I mean, there's many communication tools
out there.
So what tool should we be utilizing when
we are communicating with one another.
Also things like cultural differences as
well.
A phrase in one part of the
world could mean something
completely different in
another part of the world.
So again, we need to be cognizant of all
these different cultural anomalies,
cultural differences.
And so, again, how are we going to
communicate?
What's our acceptable behavior?
Again, the do's and don'ts of the team.
Also guidelines for making decisions
coming to a consensus, right?
Along with that, there's going to be
conflicts as well.
So how are we going to handle these
conflicts?
Right, there's a separate
section on conflict,
a separate video on conflict management.
But how we're going to manage these
conflicts?
How are we going to be managing these
disagreements?
That's all going to be documented here as
well.
Also, I mean, general ground rules.
I mean, that's really what the team
charter is setting.
It's setting some ground rules, ground
rules for behavior between our team members.
So really, you know, team norms, right,
team norms for meeting and decision making.
So who, if we can't come to a decision,
then how are we going
to come to a decision?
Who's going to encourage who to come up
with a decision?
And how are we going to come up with a
decision?
That's all going to be documented here in
the team charter as well.
And again, team communication guidelines.
So, you know, in summary, this is
basically documenting the team values,
communication guidelines,
decision-making process, right,
conflict resolution process,
at least conflict management.
There's a difference in conflict
resolution and conflict management.
You can't always resolve the conflict,
but you can certainly manage a conflict.
And that's what the, you know,
that's the key here.
We want to manage our conflict so it doesn't
have a negative impact on our project.
So how are we going to do that between our
team?
Again, that's all going to be documented
here in the team charter.
So again, it's just basically the do's and
don'ts of the team.
Now, another important artifact is this
one here called the Resource Calendar.
And the Resource Calendar is, as far as
PIMBox 6 is concerned, it's considered an
output of the process called Acquire
Resources.
and the resource calendar is basically
just documenting availability of
resources, both physical resources as well
as team resources, right?
So, for example, team resources.
When are team members available?
One of the rolling onto a project?
One are the rolling off a project?
One are they going on vacation?
Right?
When are they going on training?
What times are they actually available to
do the work?
Especially when you've got team members
that are not 100% working on your project?
Right, might be on your project for a
certain time period, or there might be on
your project, you know, say, you know,
50% of the time.
50% of the time is on your project,
50% of the time is on another project.
Well, what 50% of the time are they
working on your project?
What's their availability?
And then machines as well.
What's the availability of, say,
a particular machine?
This machine is being shared by,
you know, the whole organization,
different teams within the organization.
So what's the availability?
When is this machine available?
So again, that is documented in the
resource calendar.
Resource calendar then is also going to be
identifying things like work days,
shift work, holidays and so
and so forth, especially again
when you have different
populations of team members, right?
You have, for example, trade union
workers.
If you have trade union workers, you can't
assume that they could
be working overtime.
Or you have team members in foreign
countries.
You can't assume that
there's always going to
be a 40-hour work
week in a foreign country.
In different countries, have different
holidays, different weekends even,
and so on and so forth.
So if there is a location, a foreign
location that is going to be closed
because of a holiday, well,
that's going to be documented
in, you know, in some
kind of resource calendar.
So that's really what the resource
calendar is documenting, you know,
just the availability of all of our
resources.
And you're not necessarily just going to
have one resource calendar.
Really, it's going to be many resource
calendars.
For example, for a machine, right,
I mean, there's 10 machines.
Each machine is going to have their own
availability.
So each machine then will technically have
their own resource calendar when,
you know, the availability of that
particular machine.
So these are a couple of important
artifacts, a couple of important documents
that, again, that you may be asked about
on the exam.